Guide to the China Records Project Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Papers of Individuals: A - G, Series I
  - Burch, Clarence Arthur and Miriam Stuart Hewes
    - Printed Material: "Prophetic and Mission Record" includes paragraphs about Clarence and Miriam Burch, ca. 1906 (Box 304, Folder 4)
    - Typescript articles by Ruth Burch: "Chinese Stories", "The Chinese are like this", "Styles in China", 1930 (Box 304, Folder 5)
    - Typescript paper by CB: "Compassion", also incl. recognition award 1974 from congregation of 1st Christian Church of San Jose, CA (Box 304, Folder 6)
    - Bound ms.: "Personal Histories of Clarence Arthur Burch and Miriam Stuart Hewes Burch", 1988 (Box 304, Folder 7)
    - Printed material re. the Shanghai American School - "Nooze", Magazine, Yearbook, 1925, 1926, 1928-1930 (Box 304, Folder 8-13)
    - Clippings: "Nantungchow Hospital Bombing, 1930s (Box 304, Folder 14)
    - Clippings: "Burches' Sixtieth Wedding Anniversary", 1966 (Box 304, Folder 15)
    - Printed material: "The YPSI SEM Newsletter", 1929 (Box 304, Folder 16)
  - Burr, Leona
    Biog. info: ABCFM Shaowu, Foochow, Fukien
    - Correspondence, 1944-1951 (Box 357, Folder 6-7)
  - Burtt, Lucy
    Quaker on the staff of Yenching University
    - Letters related to Friends Centre of Yenching University at time of Communist takeover, 1949 (Box 385, Folder 13)
  - Butler, Rosa May
    Biog. info: MES Shanghai, Soochow (L.1935-L.1940)
    - Correspondence, 1938-1951 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Caldwell, Mary W.
    Biog. info: PS Taichow, Kiangsu (1926)
    - Photographs primarily of Kansu Province (Selected photographs available in IMPA: http://www.usc.edu/isd/archives/arc/digarchives/mission/), ca. 1926 (Box 35, Folder 5-6)
  - Caldwell, Pearl
    Biog. info: Southern Baptist, North China 1910-1947. First folder contains more detailed biographical information and description of collection
    - Family correspondence: attending Woman's Missionary Union Training School in Louisville, KY, mission work in Louisville, 1908-1909 (Box 344, Folder 1)
    - Family correspondence: Travel to China, learning language, description of Chinese life; stationed in Lai Chow Fu, Shantung, 1910-1911 (Box 344, Folder 2)
    - Family correspondence: Visiting Chinese homes and churches, country trips, 1912-1913 (Box 344, Folder 3)
    - Family correspondence: comments on effect of WWI in China, trip to Chefoo, to country churches, 1914-1915 (Box 344, Folder 4)
    - Family correspondence: stationed in Pingtu, trip to Chefoo, teaching activities, 1937 (Box 344, Folder 5)
    - Family correspondence: fragments and undated, no date (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - General correspondence: PC to/from others, in alphabetical order (Box 344, Folder 7-9)
    - General correspondence: letters of others, 1912 (Box 344, Folder 10)
    - Writings and notes: including "Home in China", "In China Today" (Box 344, Folder 11)
    - Writings and notes: scraps of paper with devotional, notes, quotations, etc. (Box 344, Folder 12-17)
    - Biographical documentation: notes regarding call to missions, financial papers (Box 345, Folder 18)
    - Photographs: PC, missionaries and friends, American and Chinese individuals and groups, scenery (Box 345, Folder 19-23)
    - Collected material: pages from devotional books, magazines, tracts, card, Chinese language booklets (Box 345, Folder 24-25)
    - Collected material: Minutes of Annual Meeting of North China Mission of the Southern Baptist Convention, 1936 (Box 345, Folder 26)
    - Collected material: Chinese language banners and papers, folded paper scrolls (Box 345, Folder 27-29)
  - Campbell, Alice Joy
    Biog. info: A teacher at Lingnan University in Canton and circa 1938 married L.K. Little, who was then commissioner of customs in Canton.
    - Photograph album: Hong Kong, Shameen Island, Canton, 1936 Aug - 1937 May (Box 305, Folder 1)
    - Photograph album: Hong Kong, Shameen Island, Japanese occupation of Canton, 1937-1938 (Box 305, Folder 2)
    - Photograph album: Canton, Hong Kong, Henan Province, Kwangsi Province, 1936-1938 (Box 305, Folder 3)
    - Loose photographs: Canton falls to Japanese army, 1938 (Box 305, Folder 4)
    - Loose photographs: Family, 1938-1940 (Box 305, Folder 5)
    - Photographs: Photos of China, mostly Canton, 1930s-1940 (Box 306, Folder 1-8)
  - Carleton, Mary Elaine (M.D.)
    WFMS Mintsing, Fu. (L.1916-L.1926)
    - News paper clippings: Obituary re. Mary E. Carleton, 1927 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Carr, Ruth M. White (Mrs. Clarence)
    Biog. info: WFMS Mintsing, Fu. (L.1916-L.1926)
    - Personal items, incl. Life Motto 24 March 1914 copied from Ruth M. White's Bible at a later date by her motherLife Motto 24 March 1914 copied from Ruth M. White's Bible at a later date by her mother, ca. 1917-1931 (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence: Letters from RMWC to her parents Mr and Mrs. Charles L. White, New York, 1917 Jun- 1918 Mar (Box 36, Folder 3-30)
    - Correspondence: Letters to Ruth M. White, Jul 1917 (Box 36, Folder 31-34)
    - Correspondence: Letters to Ruth M. White, 1917 Aug - 1918 Feb (Box 36, Folder 35-37)
    - Correspondence: Letters and postcards to others, etc, Jun-Sep1917 (Box 36, Folder 38-44)
    - Correspondence: Letters from RMWC, 1918 Mar-Dec (Box 36, Folder 45-46)
    - Ms. (Chinese) written by RMWC's teacher, Mar 1918 (Box 36, Folder 47)
    - Biographical Data on Truman H. Newberry probably copied by Mrs. C.L. White. Mrs. Newberry was Ruth White's sponsor, Aug 1917 (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Newspaper clipping: "Community Shows Its Love....", Jul 1917 (Box 36, Folder 49)
    - Written Material: Chinese language (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Typescript Material: "Church Union", "What can we do to unite the Christian Force in Peking?" Papers read at the Peking Missionary Association by Dr. T.T. Lew, Dr. Li Jung Fang and Miss Wood., 1926 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Typescript Material incl. "Who's Who" Y.W.C.A, 1917, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Misc. incl. dry leaves, postcard, Chinese National flag, etc., 1917-1918 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Printed Material incl. "The Street of Precious Pearls" by Nora Waln, "The Seven Lamps of Asia", etc., 1921-1945 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Printed Material incl. "Just a word about China Steam Filature", "Democracy in Modern China", "China's War and Peace Aims", 1917-1945 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Diagram Peking Y.W.C.A, 1917 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Printed Material: Pictures of China, Kitchen God, wrapping paper, etc. (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Printed Material (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Diaries of RMWC, 1917-1926 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Letters from RMWC to her parents, 1919-1926 (Box 38, Folder 1-11)
  - Carson, F. Stanley
    Biog. info: MEFB Hinghwa (1905-1942)
    - Correspondence and biographical sketch of F. Stanley Carson, 1970 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Carter, Alice
    Biog. info: PN Siangtan, Hunan. Carter worked at a hospital in Siangtan.
    - Two volumes of edited letters written by Alice Carter to her sister Helen Greene. Early letters describe Carter's time at the Nanking Language School., 1920-1924 (Box 339, Folder 2-3)
  - Chandler, Robert E. and Helen
    ABCFM, Tientsin, Foochow
    - 4 circular letters, 1920-1947 (Box 376, Folder 16)
  - Chang, Alois
    Father Alois Chang served the Catholic Mission Llan/Fukuoli in Taiwan.
    - Two letters in German addressed to Frl. Elsbeth Gremminger; two photographs of Father Chang, 1963 (Box 372, Folder 4)
  - Chang, Fu-liang
    Biog. info: Born in 1889; Ph.B. and M.F. from Yale (1913,1915); Prof. and Dean, Yale-in-China, Changsha (1915-1926); National Secretary in charge of rural work, NCC of China (1927-1934); Sec. Ge., Chinese Industrial Cooperatives, Inc. (1945-1948); Regional Dir., Chinese-American Joint Commission on Rural Reconstruction (1948-1949); Prof. of Sociology, Berea College, Berea, KY (1951-1959)
    - Correspondence: Letters primarily to Fu-liang Chang, 1946-1970 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Typescript Material: Biographical mat. re. Fu-liang Chang, 1949-1972 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Typescript writings incl. "Cooperation", "The new Life in China", "The Christian Message to the Chinese Farmer", "How to increase rural income", etc., 1936-1947 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Typescript writings incl. "The Yale-in-China Spirit", "Chinese Industrial Cooperatives", etc., 1948-1950 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Typescript writings incl. "The Foreign Christian Assistance Program", "Whither Pine Mountain", "Partners in Quest of a Good Life", etc., 1951-1957 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Typescript writings incl. "China Revisited", "Family Mottos for New South Kiangsi", etc., 1966-1972 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Typescript material re. Chinese Industrial Cooperatives, 1943-1948 (Box 40, Folder 7-9)
    - Typescript material re. Joint Commission on Rural Reconstruction, Oct 1948- 1949 Dec, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 10-15)
    - Typescript material: misc. subject material, 1942-1958 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Chao, Jacob
    Jacob Chao served with the Catholic Missin of Tsinan, Shantung.
    - Letter to P. J. Kranz describes civil war and disruptions from Communist forces in Tsinan area., 1947 Feb 20 (Box 372, Folder 5)
  - Chauvenet, Annie
    Biog. info: Traveled to China in the 1880s
    - Early photographs of Peking and environs., 1880s (Box 42, Folder 1-51)
  - Cheng Ching-yi
    - Printed Material: brochure on Cheng Ching-Yi Memorial Church Kweiyang, Kweichow, 1939 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Chester, Ruth M.*
    Biog info: Ginling College Nanking, Chengtu (1917-1950)
    - Typescript letters (edited excerpts) Nanking, Shanghai and Chengtu, 1927-1950 (Box 39, Folder 3-18)
    - Typescript report: "Impressions of Ginling in Nanking" by RMC, Jan 1946 (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - Typescript radio script: "Women in Wartime China" by RMC, May 1941 (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - Biographical material compiled by Edith G.D. Hsiung, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Clapp, Dwight Howard
    Clapp was an ABCFM missionary in Shansi who was killed during the Boxer uprising in 1900.
    - Artifact: A decorative printed cloth enclosure with folded paper design within. This item was made at the Shansi Mission in Tai-ku and brought to the U.S. on furlough in 1894. (Box 372, Folder 6)
  - Clark, Irving B.
    - Misc. - Photographs, passport, telegram and telegraph receipts, 1906, 1915 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Cochran, Mary Williams
    Biog. info: PN Daughter of John E. Williams and Lilian Caldwell Williams. John Williams was an educational missionary in Nanking and became Vice-President of Nanking University. He was killed in the 1927 Nanking incident. Mary and her husband William Cochran were stationed in Paotingfu 1933-1941.
    - Memoir: "My Life in China" by MWC (1992) (Box 339, Folder 1)
  - Cooke, Alma
    ABCFM, North China, medical
    - Circular letter, 1947 (Box 376, Folder 17)
  - Coole, Arthur Bradden
    Biog. info: MEFB Tientsin, Peking, Chungking, Shanghai, Kutien, Fukien, Yenching University (1906-1948)
    - Printed material: Information on Chinese numismatics by ABC. Encyclopedia of Chinese Coins, Vol. I, 1966-1967 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Cormack, James Grieve
    Biog. info: CIM evangelist Cheng Tu, Tibetan villages 1890s-1900; returned to Scotland to complete medical education at Edinburgh University; senior medical missionary LMS 1917-1925 serving in Hankow, Shanghai, Peking; Principal and Dean of Peking Union Medical College; 1925 returned to Scotland; died 1934.
    - Copies of two letters written by Cormack from Kiating and Hankow, addressed to "Dear friends." The letters describe preliminary rioting and attacks on Christian missionaries in West China, before the bigger riots over proposed railway expansion into the West., 1892 Nov, 1895 Jul (Box 351, Folder 4)
  - Corpron, Douglas S.*
    Biog. info: UCMS Hofei, An. Luchowfu, An. Nanking (L.1924-L.1940)
    - Typescript: "China Notes", 1949 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Craighill, Marian (Mrs. Lloyd R.)
    Biog. info: ACM Nanchang, Anking, Wuhu (L.1916-L.1940)
    - Collected Material incl. "The Miracle of Hong Kong" (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Letters to her family, 1915-1919 (Box 49, Folder 2-13)
    - Correspondence: Letters to her family, 1920-1927 (Box 50, Folder 1-12)
    - Correspondence: Letters to her family, 1928-1932 (Box 51, Folder 1-12)
    - Correspondence: Letters to her family, 1933-1937 (Box 52, Folder 1-11)
    - Correspondence: Letters to her family, 1938-1940 (Box 53, Folder 1-6)
    - Correspondence: Letters (fragments) (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Letters and other materials related to Lloyd R. Craighill, 1918-1943 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Collected material, n.d. (Box OV4)
  - Crawford, O.C.*
    Biog. info: PN Soochow, Hangchow (1900-1939)
    - Typescript: "Diary", 1938-1939 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Cressey, Paul F.
    Biog. info: ABFMS Swatow (1921-1924)
    - Detailed map and photos of ABFMS Compound at Swatow; Letter and curriculum vita of PFC, also incl. invitations and calling cards (Box 248, Folder 1)
    - Photo album; two mounted photos, 1921-1924 (Box 248, Folder 2)
  - Crook, R.L. and Edith Loree
    Biog. info: UCC; ABFMS Chengtu, Szechuan; Yaan, Sekang (1919-1951)
    - Newsletter (untitled); letter re. evacuation from China, 1951, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Cross, Helen C. Silsby (Mrs. Robert C.)
    Biog. info: PN Shanghai, Soochow, Hangchow (1913-1921); see also: Silsby, John Alfred
    - Photographs, 1920 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - misc., 1920-1951 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Letter from Helen C. Silsby Cross to friends, 1920 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Typescript report: Personal report of Helen C. Silsby, 1920-1921 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Collected Material incl. "The American Legion Magazine", English Language books, etc., 1945-1966 (Box 48, Folder 10-11)
    - Diaries (3), 1918-1920 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Cross, Laura B.
    ABCFM, North China, Bridgman Academy
    - 2 circular letters, 1947, 1950 (Box 376, Folder 18)
  - Crutcher, Ella B.
    - Typescript material Bound: "Stories and Family Memories" by Ella Crutcher, 1985 (Box 309, Folder 5)
  - Curtis, Edith
    - Photographs: 2 photos of classes in Day School in Szechuan Province (1923) (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Davidson, Sydney Arthur, Jr.
    Biog. info: MEFB (1934-1939)
    - Typescript articles: "Mint Sing, "Min River", "Taoism" by S.A. Davidson Jr., Foochow, Fukien (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Typewritten Ms.: copies of articles on S.A. Davidson Jr. incl. excerpts from his letters. Brockton, Mass. (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook of correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1934-1939 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1935-1938 (Box 357, Folder 8)
    - Writings, 1931-1938, n.d. (Box 357, Folder 9-10)
    - Tributes following his death, 1939 (Box 357, Folder 11)
  - Dawson, Mary E.S.
    Biog. info: ACM Hankow, Changsha (L.1923-L.1932)
    - Biographical Data (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Letters primarily to her family, arranged in chronological order, 1921-1931 (Box 55, Folder 2-95)
    - Poems: "Changsa" by Edith A. Madge; "A Rhyme for June 8" for Miss Dawson's birthday (8 June 1930); Riddles dealing with the names of missionaries at Hankow, 1924, 1930 (Box 55, Folder 96-98)
  - Decker, John W.
    - International Missionary Council "China Study - 1947-1948" (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - International Missionary Council "China - Misc. contacts, corres. 1944, 1955-1957" (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - International Missionary Council, materials related to China, 1937-1956 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - International Missionary Council, "China -Reference Material, 1927-1957 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - International Missionary Council, "China study re. Washington Conference on China Policy Oct 1949", 1949-1950 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - International Missionary Council "China, Crisis - 1950-1951" (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - International Missionary Council "China Study - St. Albans Meeting July 1951" (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - "China Study", 1953-1955 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - "China Study - M Searle Bates 1956" (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - International Missionary Council "China - Misc. contacts - reports, minutes, etc. 1956-1957" (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - De Jong, Nettie R.
    Biog. info: PN Honan Changteh, Changsha, Hunan (L.1921-L.1936)
    - Photographs: Foreign missionaries and Chinese Christian Soldiers, 1932 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Typescript reports and papers, 1923-1942 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1938 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Misc. collection incl. map of China, Chinese language material, poster of Chinese kitchen god, map of Chang ten. (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1919-1945 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - 11 letters from NRD to Margaret Fisher (Gohl), written from Changteh, Changsha, Kuling, New York, and Michigan, 1922-1931 (Box 351, Folder 5)
  - De Vargas, Philippe
    ABCFM; YMCA Peking, Hankow, Hup. Yenching Univ. (L.1916-L.1940)
    - Writings by Philippe De Vargas incl. "Some Elements in the Chinese Renaissance", "The History of Cultural Relations between China and the West", etc., 1917-1949 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Annotated bibliography, 1938-1939 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Memorial Statement re. De Vargas, 1956 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Dewar, Mary Reed
    - N.C.C.C. Mary Dewar Papers: General letters, 1947-1951 (Box 59, Folder 1-10)
    - Typescript letters and reports, 1947-1950 (Box 60, Folder 1-8)
    - National Council of Churches, 1950 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Recognition of Government in China by the United States Signatures to memorandum, 1950 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Dewey, Carol M.
    Biog. info: MEFB Peking, Chengtu (1921-1947)
    - Photographs and postcards, etc., 1949 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Dickson, Lillian R.
    Biog. info: "The Mustard Seed" mission, Taiwan (1927-1975)
    - Correspondence - Book I incl. writings "From Formosa", "Who will Lead Us?" Letters to friends, Letters to Marilyn, 1936, 1945-1953, 1967-1968 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - Book II Letters to daughter Marilyn and her family, 1947-1967 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence - Book III Letters by Lillian, James and Marilyn to family and friends. Also writings "Return to Formosa" and others, 1941-1976 (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - Book IV Writings "Light for the Mountains", "The Ne Year in a Chinese Home", "Into the Mountains", "God's Plan", "Report on Formosa", circular letters, letters to Marilyn, 1935-1968 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - Book V Circular letters from Taiwan, 1970-1975 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - Book VI Circular letters from Taiwan, 1975-1980 (Box 135, Folder 2)
    - Collected Material: Brochures and pamphlets re. The Mustard Seed, Inc. (Box 135, Folder 3)
    - Collected Material: Reader's Digest reprint - "Littlest Lady with the Biggest Heart", "Rosy Thoughts for Cross Cultural Living", 1962 (Box 135, Folder 4)
    - Collected Material: Video - "While it is Day" (Box 135, Folder 5)
    - Collected Material: News clippings, excerpts from letters (Box 135, Folder 6)
    - Photographs: Lillian, and with others (Box 135, Folder 7)
  - Dilley, Frederick Edwards Dilley, Mary Grace (French)
    PN Peking, Cheloo, Shantung (1906-1942)
    - Photographs: "Peoples", 1921-1955 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Circular letters to friends, 1932-1961 (Box 62, Folder 3-4)
    - Collected Material incl. "ECF News", "Temple Hill Hospital", etc., 1911-1969 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Dodd Family
    Biog. info: Samuel Dodd and Sarah Green Dodd, David Green and Lydia Goodrich Green, I. S. F. Dodd; Ningpo and Hangchow (1861-1878) (1859-1869) medical missionary (1890s)
    - Biographical Material, 1982 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Drew, Florence
    Biog. info: South China Boat Mission Canton (1909-1932)
    - Pamphlet re. South China Boat Mission: "Some Personal Reminiscences of Miss Florence Drew" (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Ellis, Emery Ward
    Biog. info: ABCFM Lintsin, Techow (1904-1927)
    - Correspondence, 1911-1917 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Letters to family, 1934, 1942-1945 (Box 63, Folder 2-3)
    - Correspondence: Letters of sympathy to Mrs. Ellis, etc, 1946 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1952 (Box 63, Folder 5-10)
    - Typescript Material incl. "UNESCO audio-visual project", "The farm village experiment - Toward a Christian village", Bulletin, a play script, etc., 1928-1952 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Typescript Report: "An Experiment in Teaching the Christian Religion by Life Situations in Fen Village" (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Collected Material: "Chinese Church Hymnal", Chinese language material (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Printed material, 1938-1953 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Personal and Memorabilia, 1899-1946 (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - Poetry: "In Memoriam - Emery Ward Ellis 1876-1946" by EWE, [Minnie Case Ellis?-his wife], and a parishioner (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - Misc. collection: "Ribbons", 1895-1900 (Box 63, Folder 17)
    - Photographs, 1922 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1893, 1910 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook, 1920-1931 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1946 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Collected material: Chinese game sheet, illustrated map of Tungchou, sheet from "Oberlin Times", 1938,n.d. (Box OVd5)
  - Ely, Lois Anna
    Biog. info: UCMS Tungchow, Kiangsu (1918- )
    - Correspondence: Letter from Lois Anna Ely to friends at home, 1941 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Evans, Philip S., Jr., M.D. and Evans, Mary Levering
    Biog. info: SBC Yangchow, Kiangsu Nanking Shantung Xn. Univ. (1900-1940)
    - Correspondence: Letters to his family, 1905-1908, 1923-1934 (Box 66, Folder 1-22)
    - Photographs (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Letters to his family, 1905,1935-1940 (Box 67, Folder 2-8)
    - Correspondence: Mary Levering Evans letters, 1926-1940 (Box 67, Folder 9-13)
    - Correspondence: Letters of children of PSE, Jr. and MLE, 1927-1934, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Miscellany: Article by PSE, Sr. (1905), article re. opening of Baptist Hospital at Yangchow (1908), notes re. China (n.d), obituary of MLE (1957) (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - Miscellany: Description of World Mission tour taken by Dr. and Mrs. J. Levering Evans, 1963 (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - Photograph: family, 1926 (Box 201, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Letters from PSE to children, 1921-1924 (Box 201, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Letters from MLE to children, 1922-1925 (Box 201, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Letter to PSE Jr. from colleagues at University of Nanking Medical School, 1917 (Box 201, Folder 4)
    - Handwritten ms: Biographical information re. PSE and MLE (Box 201, Folder 5)
    - Typescript ms: Biographical information re. PSE Sr., The funeral service of PSE, 1913 (Box 201, Folder 6)
    - Typescript ms: Info. re. Dr. W.E. Macklin - "Dr. macklin - a "most unforgettable character" by PSE III (Box 201, Folder 7)
    - Plans for house in Kuling (Box OVd3)
  - Fagg, John Gerardus and Margaret Gillespie Fagg
    Stationed in Amoy 1887-1894, serving under the Reformed Church in America. After return to U.S. Fagg (d. 1917) served as a pastor and member of the RCA Board of Foreign Missions and Margaret Fagg was a leader in the RCA Women's Missionary Society.
    - Two diaries of Margaret Fagg written as the Faggs traveled to Scotland where Mrs. Fagg was a speaker at the Sixth Conference of the International Union of Women's Foreign Missionary Societies of the Presbyterian and Reformed Churches; program from conference, 1913 (Box 372, Folder 7)
    - Three diaries of Margaret Fagg, 1935, 1940, 1941 (Box 372, Folder 8)
    - Re. Diamond Jubilee of Amoy Mission, R.C.A. and John Gerardus Fagg Memorial Hospital, 1920s (Box 372, Folder 9)
    - Sermons and pamphlets by John and Margaret Fagg, Memorial service for John Fagg, 1895-1917, no date (Box 372, Folder 10)